# IAN OTTO

### DEVELOPER AND INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST

#### INFO

**PHONE** 9288300385

EMAIL ian@duper51.me

# LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

### SKILLS

JavaScript

••••

Linux Systems Administration

• • • •

Information Security

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

Java

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

РНР

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

Python

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

Databases

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$ 

HTML/CSS

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$ 

### PROFILE

Experienced developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer and network security industry. Skilled in Systems Administration, Linux, Java, Bash, and much more. Focused computer engineer working on a BS of Computer Science from Northern Arizona University.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Information Security Student Worker, Northern Arizona University

Flagstaff

Oct 2016 - Present

Developed and maintained a phishing reporting application. Worked on best practices documentation used across campus. Dissected malware to determine purpose and security risk. Performed security analysis on university applications to determine risk.

# Founder, Perfection Hosting

Jan 2013 - Jul 2016

Developed a backend service for provisioning, start/stop jobs, etc. Handled high-level support tickets for debugging and provisioning errors. Developed custom code for several clients.

Jan 2019 - Jan 2019

# **EDUCATION**

# Northern Arizona University, Bachelor of Computer Science

Flagstaff

Aug 2016 - May 2020

Acquired basic and advanced computer science knowledge from many courses. Was active in ACM, and worked on many projects outside of classes, such as a bus ETA aggregation app.

### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

Hack Arizona Tuscon

Developed a fully functional shell application within 36 hours from scratch. Won a Raytheon embedded systems hacking challenge in first place.

## REFERENCES

# Mr. Daniel Wallace from Northern Arizona University

Daniel.Wallace@nau.edu